Jorge García

www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-garcia-45545790 Portfolio:https://jorest.github.io/

SUMMARY

Creative engineer, who likes to learn new things. I have experience working with multidisciplinary teams, with the ability to communicate and discuss new ideas. Experienced mainly as a programmer, and passionate about game design especially game mechanics and narrative.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Self-taught | Creativity | Collaboration | Analytical skills | Scripting | Communication | Unity | Version control | Game design | Problem-solving

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Game Developer

11/2019 -03/2020

- Developing responsive web games templates using Javascript.
- Creating fun and casual games

IT Engineer, Ericsson

03/2019 - 09/2019

- Worked under the supervision of senior IT Engineers to implement, test, deploy, and support new features and fixes.
- Worked both with Git and SVN.

VR Developer, Optimus View

03/2018 - 10/2018

- Developed VR applications using Unity(C#) + Oculus to showcase real-estate properties.
- Requirement gathering and customer liaising
- Optimized the frame per second, to be able to run the projects in lower spec machines.
- Worked with graphic designers, to make the features and UI work well together.

- Game Designer for El Chavo Playbook Acalulpo
- Communicated with art, production, and programming teams to design innovative game elements that kids could enjoy

EDUCATION

Computer Science Engineering

01/2013 - 12/2018

Universidad del Valle de Guatemala.

Academic achievements:

- distinguished student 2015,2016
- Kept a Scholarship for five years
- Abroad semester at *University of the Basque Country 2016*

CERTIFICATES

- Michigan's State University Principles of Game Design
- Linkedin Game Design Foundations (1,2,3)
- ETS TOEFL 102/120

LANGUAGES

• Spanish: Native

• **English**: Professional working proficiency

• **German**: Beginner